片名  亡命天涯
走吧  医生
Come on, Doc.
记者在金波医生住宅
Reporting live from the home...
现场报导
...of Dr. Richard Kimble...
他是芝加哥当地的名医
...a respected vascular surgeon at Chicago Memorial Hospital.
目前案子尚不明朗
Details are sketchy...
只知道金波夫人在今夜遇害
...but we understand Dr. Kimble's wife, Helen, was found murdered this evening.
警方陪同金波走出来了
Area Six detectives are bringing Dr. Kimble out.
可能要带他去警局
We assume that they're gonna be taking him to a police station,
录他的口供
probably Area Six...
希望他对今晚的事能有所交待
...where they hope he can shed some light on what happened here this evening.
金波夫人在午夜前不久遇害
Now, as I indicated, she was found shortly before midnight.
遇害前她打过911电话
We know that she made apparently a 911 call to police...
说她遭到陌生人攻击
...indicating that she was being assaulted by an intruder.
情况尚不明朗
Details are very sketchy.
据闻金波夫妇...
We do know that he and his wife Helen...
今晚曾到四季大饭店
...were at the Four Seasons Hotel earlier tonight...
参加一场募款餐会...
...a fundraiser for the Children's Research Fund.
理查  还记得卡罗吗?
Rich, remember Cara?
-卡罗  你好  -幸会
-Nice to see you. -Nice to see you.
手臂要伸直才行
Straighten that arm or you're gonna slice.
高尔夫专家教你的?
Golf pro teach you that?
我妻子教的
My wife.
先说一声...
Before I forget...
谢谢你借车给我  钥匙在楼下
...thanks for the loaner. Keys are downstairs.
-还有汽油吧? -够你用了
-Any gas in it? -Yes. Enough.
艾力克  这是金波医生
Alec, Richard Kimble.
-你好  -金波医生
-How are you? -Dr. Kimble!
可以  随时侯教
absolutely, any time
这主意不错
I think this is a good idea
好了  就说到这里
Knock it off!
这儿没搞头  跟我走吧  失陪
There's nothing to see here. And you, come with me.
多谢解围  我快找不到话题了
Thank you. I was just down to my last joke.
你今晚很美  海伦
You look really beautiful tonight.
谢谢
Thanks, honey.
我知道你讨厌应酬  但你穿礼服很帅
I know you hate these things, but God, I love looking at you in a tux.
觉得自己像个服务生
I feel I look like a waiter or something.
喂
Hello
-金波医生  -是的
-Dr. Kimble? -Yes, it is.
打扰了
Sorry to bother you, sir...
史帝芬医生在手术房要你去支援
...but Dr. Stevens is in Emergency Surgery and needs your help.
我马上赶去
Call him back and tell him I'll be right there.
多谢
Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢  晚安
Thank you. Good night.
我等你回来
I'll wait up for you.
是什么情况? 告诉我
Talk to me. What have we here?
谢谢你赶来
Thanks for coming.
病人58岁  刚切除胆囊  还在流血
A 58-year -old. Just pulled his gallbladder. Bleeding.
腹上部大量流血
Big time. It's in the liver bed.
-血液凝结的速度如何? -不正常
-What are his coags? -They're all messed up.
血压是36  其他的失去控制了
PT's 36 and the rest are off the wall.
怎么送进来的?
Where is he from?
蓝兹医生的病人  但找不到他
Lentz's name is on the chart. We paged him, but no answer.
我去看看  让开一些
Here guys. Let me in there. Give me some room.
止血夹给我
Give me a clamp.
抽积血
Give me suction.
你上班的地方有人恐吓你吗?
Have you been getting any threats at work?
同僚  医院员工  任何人?
Co workers, hospital staff, anyone?
没有
No
有碰到异常情况吗?
Anything unusual going on...
有人打电话来  再突然挂掉?
...phone calls, people hanging up?
任何不速之客  推销员?
Maybe people coming to the door? Tradespeople?
就我所知没有
Not that I know of.
谈谈你跟独臂人打斗的经过
Back to this fight with this guy with one arm.
在楼上或楼下打?
Did it happen upstairs or downstairs?
楼上
Upstairs.
他在右臂或左臂...
And he had which? A right or a left arm?
装着义肢?
With a gimmick on it?
右臂
Right arm.
是带着勾子的那一种?
Is it one of those with the hooks, or...
不是  是普通的义肢
No, he had a cosmetic hand.
你家里的保全系统还不错
The security system in your house, it's a pretty good one.
有其他人知道密码吗?
Anyone else have the coding?
佣人知道
Our maid.
她知道密码  也有钥匙
She knows the code and has a key.
你脖子上的抓痕...
Those scratches on your neck...
是独臂人抓的?
...did the one -armed guy do that?
我在扶起海伦时被她抓的
Helen scratched me when I was trying to move her.
跟独臂人打斗之前或之后?
Before or after you had the fight with the one -armed man?
我说过了
I told you.
你有枪吗?
You own a gun, Doc?
你拥有枪支吗?
Do you own a gun?
家里放了一把
Yes, we have a gun in the house.
用你的名字登记的?
Is it registered in your name?
没错
Yes.
平常枪都摆在哪儿?
Where do you usually keep that gun?
你那把枪
The one that you own.
摆在海伦的小桌子里
It's in Helen's table.
床边的小桌子
Bedside table.
家里平常有放珠宝之类的?
Do you keep much jewelry in the house?
你有保险箱吗? 到处有他的指纹  灯台...
His fingerprints are all over the lamp...
枪支  子弹上都有
...the gun and the bullets...
海伦的指甲内留有他的皮肉
...and the good doctor's skin is under her fingernails.
你太太娘家很有钱?
She's got the money in the family, hasn't she?
-她出身大户人家  -没错
-Helen comes from a wealthy family -yes.
她有投保吗?
Is she insured?
有投保
Yes, she is.
谁是受益人?
Who's the beneficiary?
我
I am.
你是唯一受益人?
The sole beneficiary?
是的
Yes.
金钱方面  你能得到点好处
Financially, you won't be hurting after this, will you?
她的命值不少钱呢
I mean, she was worth quite a bit of money.
你怀疑我杀了自己的妻子?
Are you suggesting that I killed my wife?
敲碎她的头颅  再一枪打死?
You're saying that I crushed her skull and shot her.
你敢含血喷人
How dare you!
我返家后  发现一个陌生人
When I came home, there was a man in my house.
跟他打斗
I fought with this man.
个持枪男子  他有一个机械手臂
The one-armed man.He had a mechanical arm.
-塑料还是橡胶? -你们快去抓他
-Plastic? Rubber? -You find this man!
快去抓他
You find this man!
他有多高?
How tall?
他害得我好惨
He took everything from me.
我的老天
Oh, Jesus.
-他大约多重? -天啊
-What did he weigh? -Oh, Jesus.
头发是什么颜色?
What color was his hair?
眼睛什么颜色?
What color were his eyes?
你不说我们无法帮你
We can't help you if you don't help us.
控告他
Book him.
陪审团的先生女士...
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
金波的罪状铁证如山
...you will hear iron-clad proof of Richard Kimble's guilt.
科学上的证据  百口莫辩
Indisputable scientific evidence...
在1月20日的晚间
...that on the night of January 20...
金波以毒手
...Richard Kimble did in fact viciously...
殴打...
...attack...
并残暴地杀害他的夫人
...and brutally murder his wife.
你们还会听到
But you'll hear more than that.
金波夫人在九泉之下
You will hear a voice from the grave.
指认这位凶手的不平之鸣
The voice of Helen Kimble identifying her killer...
凶手是她的亲夫  理查金波
...her husband, Richard Kimble.
凯利警探
Detective Kelly...
当晚你在凶宅目睹了些什么?
tell us what you observed at the home of the victim on the night of the murder.
没有歹徒破门而入的痕迹
No forcible entry was found.
从调查一开始  这就不像闯空门的案子
From the beginning of the investigation, it didn't appear to be a break -in.
没有任何财物失窃
Nothing was missing.
我回来了
Honey, I'm home.
哪一队赢了?
Who won the game?
枪支  子弹上都有他的指纹
His prints were on the gun and bullets.
没有其他人的指纹
No other sets were found, other than the housekeeper's...
除了佣人及死者的以外
...and the deceased's.
金波夫人头颅破裂  造成脑部严重受损
Mrs. Kimble's skull fracture caused a massive hemorrhage to the brain.
5分钟内即死亡
It took less than 5 minutes for her to die.
庭上  我们要求重播...死者那通911电话的内容
Your Honor, we would ask to play Helen Kimble's 911 emergency call...
芝加哥警方指认的那通电话
...previously identified by a Chicago Police Department dispatcher.
911紧急中心
Emergency 911.
救救我
Please help me.
出了什么事?
What's the problem?
他...
He's...
在这儿  还在屋内
He's still in the house.
我没听错吧
Did I hear you right?
有陌生人闯入
Someone's in your house?
他想杀死我
He's trying to kill me.
复述一次好吗
Could you repeat that, please?
这位女士
Ma'am?
他想杀死我
He's trying to kill me.
女士
Lady
暴徒还在屋内
Is your attacker still in the house?
女士
Lady
理查...
Richard...
女士
Lady
理查...
Richard...
他想杀死我
Is he trying to kill me?
金波先生
Mr. Kimble...
在考虑过本案的各种因素后
having considered all the factors and aggravation and mitigation in this case
认为你行凶之意图与手法  极尽残暴之能事
...and found the offense was brutal and indicative of wanton cruelty...
本庭因而判定将你
it's judgment of this court, you will be remanded to
送往州立监狱  注射毒剂处死
Illinois State Penitentiary where you will await execution by lethal injection...
行刑日期由州司法部长另订
...on a date to be set forth by the Attorney General of the State.
愿上帝宽恕你
May God have mercy on your soul.
-卡尔森  -有
-Carlson. -Here.
-派崔塔  -有
-Partida. -Yeah.
-卡普兰  -叫什么叫
-Copeland. -What?
你安份一点
Copeland, you be nice now.
金波
Kimble.
有
Yeah.
出发了  各位
Let's go, gentlemen.
囚车要出发了
Four prisoners coming out.
上车  各位
Let's go, gentlemen.
金波  你坐这儿
Kimble, you're here.
卡尔森  坐那儿
Carlson, right over there.
派崔塔  坐前方
Partida, up front left.
卡普兰  你跟我坐后面
Copeland, you're back here with me.
放轻松
Come on, make yourselves comfortable.
各位  规矩都知道了吧
You know the routine, gentlemen.
我好累
I'm tired.
到米纳镇路程约20英里
20 miles from Menard.
40分钟内可以抵达
We'll be there in about 40 minutes.
早到早放心  让典狱长去照料
I'll be glad to get rid of this load. Let McKenzie take care of them.
那边的伙食不错  我饿扁了
Always got some good eating there. I'm starving.
我也一样
Me, too.
牢饭吃够了
Had enough prison chow.
艾德才不管呢  反正他在节食
Old Ed, he don't care. His old lady's got him on a diet.
对吧  艾德
Right, Ed?
快过来  快
Somebody get in here, quick!
他病了  赶快
He's getting sick! Let's go move! Move!
-口吐白沫  -快到了
-He's foaming at the mouth. -We're almost at the prison.
他喘不过气了...
He's choking!
等等
Wait!
天呀  妈的
Oh, shit!
金波  快来  你是医生  快帮忙
Kimble, get over here. You're a doctor, do something!
手铐打开
Unlock me!
接住
Catch
撑住你不会有事的
You'll be okay.
什么声音
What the hell is that?
妈的
Shit!
-帮我一把  -去你的
-Help me! -The hell with you.
帮个忙
Help me with this man!
去你的  医生
Fuck your doctor
听好...
Now you listen.
我不管你往哪个方向逃
I don't give a damn which way you go.
别跟着我  懂吗
Just don't follow me. You got that?
是的
Yes
卡普兰
Kaplan
保重
Be good.
我的老天
My, my, my.
乱得一塌糊涂
What a mess.
比马戏团还乱
It's a circus.
我的袋子在你那儿吗?
You got my bag?
这儿被火车撞个正着
Point of impact right here.
车头分解  其余车厢出轨
The first engine uncoupled, and the train jumped the track.
出轨后又滑行了约100码
About 100 yards?
是的
Yes
该买双新靴子
You must get new boots.
早说过  不要穿高跟鞋
I told you not to wear the heels.
穿两件外套
Wear two coats.
下次吧
Next train wreck.
干嘛呵护她
Why do we always mother her?
因为她爱我们
Because she loves us.
-你想当火车司机吗? -他大概表现得很神勇
-How'd you like to be the driver? -I bet he did a Casey Jones.
慢点  先生
Hold it, sir.
这里谁负责
Hi. Who's in charge?
罗林斯警长
Sheriff Rollins.
在电视台记者那边
Just follow the TV lights.
罗吉斯警长
Sheriff Rogers.
他叫罗林斯
Rollins!
去出事现场看看
Look down there and take Newman.
好
Ok
该上工了
Come on. Time to go to work.
巴士翻滚了好几次才停住
The bus rolled over several times before settling down at the bottom of the hill.
我不晓得是否昏过去...
I don't know if I passed out or what...
但火车突然山崩似的压过来
...but when I looked up, the train was bearing down on us. Fast.
我也搞不清楚  想不起来
I don't know how. It's still kind of hazy.
我抓住他  把他推出车外
Somehow I grabbed him and pushed him out of the bus.
-你很勇敢  没弄好的话会送命  -我了解
-You're brave, you could've been killed. -I know.
他是我的好友  义不容辞
He's my partner. He would have done the same for me.
打扰了  我是联邦副司法官吉拉  想跟你谈一谈
Excuse me, I'm Deputy U.S. Marshal Samuel Gerard, I'd like to...
你稍等一下
I'll be with you in just a minute.
可以
sure
再核对一次笔录
One more time, just for the record...
-这3位死亡了? -是的
-these three are dead. -Yes
这一位呢?
And this one?
事情发生太快...
Everything happened so fast.
他大概未及脱逃
I don't think he made it.
你白跑一趟了
You came a long way for nothing.
尊敬的警长  我想我该建议
With all due respect, Sheriff Rollins...
在15英里范围内实施路检
...I'd like to recommend checkpoints on a 15-mile radius...
包括57及24号公路  这条路也要查...
...at I-57, I-24 and over here on Route 13...
等等  犯人都死了
Wait. The prisoners are all dead.
路检只会让许多人发疯
Checkpoints will get a lot of people frantic
我办公室电话会响个不停
and they'll flood my office with calls.
我不想这种事发生  那么...
Well, shit, I'd hate to see that happen...
案子由我接管好了
...so I'll take over your investigation.
谁授权的?
On what authority?
伊利诺州州长...
The governor...
及联邦司法官办事处
...the U.S. Marshal's Office...
伊利诺州第5分局
...5th District, Northern Illinois.
好吧  这个烂摊子都交给你了
All right, you want jurisdiction over this mess. You got it.
各位  集合一下
Okay, boys, gather around and listen up.
我们收队  "西部大警长"来了
We're shutting it down. Wyatt Earp is here to mop up...
寻我开心  "西部大警长"
That's very funny, Wyatt Earp.
山姆
Sam.
瞧这个
Look here!
我们很好奇  脚链上的脚不见了
We're always fascinated when we find leg irons with no legs in them.
钥匙是谁保管的?
Who held the key, sir?
你在问我吗?
Me.
钥匙呢?
Where're those keys at?
不晓得
I don't know.
要更改你的说法吗  先生?
Care to revise your statement, sir?
什么?
What?
你编的鬼故事该修改了
Do you want to change your bullshit story, sir?
犯人可能逃走了
He might've got out.
-可能逃走了  -你说他埋在...
-He might've got out. -You said he was part of the wreckage!
马上设立行动组  大家听着
Set up operations by the fire truck. Listen, everyone!
有个犯人脱逃90分钟
A fugitive has been on the run for 90 minutes.
在崎岖的路面上  受伤的人的时速是4英里
Average foot speed over uneven ground, barring injury, is four miles an hour.
他应该还在6英里范围内
That gives us a radius of six miles.
大家逐屋逐户地去搜索  加油站
What I want out of each and everyone of you is a hard target search of every
民宅  仓库  鸡舍
...residence, warehouse, farmhouse, hen house, outhouse...
狗窝都要搜  就在这个范围内
...and doghouse in that area.
每15英里设一处路检
Checkpoints go up at 15 miles.
逃犯的大名是理查金波医生
Your fugitive's name is Dr. Richard Kimble.
逮他回来
Go get him.
医院
少来这一套
Please don't give me shit.
死了3个人  叫他听电话
I got three very unhappy dead people. Put him on.
史帝芬  我是柯斯莫
Stevens, it's Cosmo.
我马上架设卫星电话
I'll have a satellite telephone hookup in two seconds.
找到犯人血迹了
Chester Police just found a blood trail...
在西南方两英里处
...two miles southwest.
罗勃  比对一下犯人的血型
Match that blood against the prisoners'.
伦费尔
Renfer
把金波的资料传到每个医院
Get a fax I.D. on Kimble to every local hospital.
再召集州警
And follow that with troopers.
梅文
Meiwen
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我在思考
I'm thinking.
拿点咖啡跟甜甜圈给我
Think me up some coffee and a doughnut with sprinkles on top...
你闲着也是闲着
...while you're thinking.
找到一名生还者
We got a live body!
生还者
A live one?
找到一名生还者
To find a survivor
动作快  撑着点  马上救你出去
Come on. Hang in there, brother. We'll get you out of here.
接好
Good access
小心地上
Carefully on the ground
叫救护车过来
Get that ambulance down here! Come on!
Get that ambulance down here
这就是你想抓的人?
Is this what you want?
就是他
That's it.
我去复印几份
I'm going to make some copies.
早安  詹森先生  早点送来了
Good morning, Mr. Johnson. I have your breakfast for you.
你渴了吧?
We're thirsty today, aren't we?
趁热吃
Eat up before this gets cold.
这儿真干燥  不是吗?
It really does get dry in here, doesn't it?
来了
Here you are.
吃一点吧
Now, you eat something, Mr. Johnson.
吃了才有力气
You need your strength.
倒霉!
Bad Luck
医生  我们在找一名逃犯  几个小时前利用车祸脱逃
Doc, we're looking for a prisoner from that wreck.
可能有受伤
He might be hurt.
他长像如何
What does he look like?
6尺1寸  180磅  褐发  褐眼  留胡子
Six -one, 180, brown hair, brown eyes, beard.
看过吗?
Seen anyone like that around?
你说的不就是我吗?
Every time I look in the mirror, pal.
除了胡子以外
Except for the beard, of course.
医生
Doc!
什么事?
What's wrong
谢了
Thanks.
-我来帮忙  -谢了  医生
-I'll give you a hand. -Thanks, Doc.
他...
It's...
情况如何?
How is he doing?
没被火车压死算是万幸
Good, considering we dug him out from under a train.
交待值班医生一声  他胃部上方戳了个洞
Tell those attending he's got a puncture in the upper gastric area.
他没检查怎么知道
How could he tell that by looking at his face?
金波的资料送来了
Background just came in from Chicago.
也该送来了
About time. What've we got?
理查金波  脉管外科  这是什么行业?
"Richard Davis Kimble, vascular surgeon." What the hell is that?
钱赚得比你多的行业
Somebody that makes more money than you.
被判谋害妻子一级罪
"Convicted of first -degree murder of his wife.
辩称清白  说是独臂人干的
"Pleaded innocent." Says a one -armed man did it.
交游广阔
Lots of friends.
很多是医生  医院员工
Doctors, hospital staff.
从他的朋友着手  先窃听他律师的电话...
We'll start there. I want phone taps. First, his lawyer.
这办不到
You'll never going to get that.
去找鲁宾法官商量...
Call Judge Rubin. Tell him I want phone taps.
你对我吼什么?
Why'd you yell at me?
我事后再告诉他细节
I'll tell him who if I'm in a good mood.
你为何不对她吼?
Why not yell at her sometimes?
-山姆  -什么事?
-sam -What's wrong
医院打来一通电话
We got a call from the hospital.
受伤的警卫说  他在急诊室门口看到金波了
The wounded guard swears he saw Kimble there.
这是大消息
That's hot.
有一部救护车也失窃了
And an ambulance is missing.
他开救护车要去哪儿?
Where the hell is he going in an ambulance?
吉拉
Gila
发现救护车了
Ambulance just spotted...
在杜佛村以西2英里  53号州公路  朝北行驶中
...two miles west of Doverville, heading north, State Highway 53.
范围越来越大
Running out of map!
地图拿出来
Get your maps out.
试音  试音  地图拿出来
Check, sound check. Get your maps out.
市内市外所有道路都报过来
I want to know all routes in and out of that town.
我们在13号公路朝北走
We're headed north on Route 13, toward the Barkley Dam.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
跟紧救护车
Don't lose that ambulance.
发现一辆救护车  在13号公路朝北行驶
Visual location of an ambulance headed north on Route 13 toward Barkley Dam.
我们将通过一座高架桥
We'll pass through a viaduct.
快打电话  召集支援人马
Get on the horn. Bring Biggs and Newman in from the south side of the viaduct.
他的速度飞快
He's hauling ass.
中间有一座隧道吗? 支援人马来了没?
Is there a tunnel between here and there? We have Biggs and Newman?
快查地图找方向
Look on your map to know how to get there.
他插翅难飞了
We got him!
检查车辆  小心
Watch out! Watch out! Watch out!
-怎么回事!  -快回去车内  先生
-What's going on? -Get back in your car, sir!
纽曼  向目标前进
Newman! Rock and roll!
在那儿放一盏灯
Put a light in there!
你找到了没有?
What do you got?
没找到
I got nothing.
-你呢? -别开玩笑了
-What do you got? -You gotta be kidding me!
-什么? -你别开玩笑了!
-What -You gotta be kidding me!
妈的...
shit!
他妈的!
封锁隧道
Seal off the tunnel! Seal it off!
他比老鼠还会钻
We got a gopher.
妈的  我这是新鞋子
Shit! I just bought these shoes.
闭嘴  柯斯莫!
Shut up, Cosmo.
往哪边走  山姆?
Which way, Sam?
我妻子不是我杀的
I didn't kill my wife!
我不在乎
I don't care!
枪放下
Put that gun down!
放下
快点
Now!
手举起来
Hands up!
手举高
Over your head!
转身
Turn around!
想吃子弹?
Richard, do you want to get shot?
听好
Pay attention!
跪下
Get down on your knees!
马上
Right now!
山姆
sam
怎么回事  他人呢?
What happened? Where'd he go?
像小飞侠一样飞下去了
He did a Peter Pan right here off this dam!
就从这儿下去
Right here!
"咻"地一声下去了
Down! Boom! Holy shit!
上帝啊!
Holy shit!
我们可以收兵了吧?
Can we go home now?
不行
No.
上帝啊!
Holy shit!
-这儿没有出口往上走  -往上
-There's no way out of here! -We must go up.
不对...
No
爬楼梯  动作快  快出去会合!
Go up the stairs! Up, up!
把水关掉  过来
Have that water turned off. Come over here.
在桥下部署两辆车4个人
Put two patrol cars on that bridge down there, four patrolmen.
沿着河边上下搜索
Have them glass this river upstream and down.
直升机在河面上100尺搜寻  要小心电线
I want a helicopter 100 feet off this river. Make him aware of these wires.
你疯了  他死了!
Are you out of your mind? He's dead!
那就更容易逮到他了
That'll make him easy to catch.
在河岸两边布置警犬...
I want hounds on both banks of this river for two miles...
上下游两英里内都要
...upstream and downstream.
-有搜救队吗? -有
-You've got a search and rescue team? -yes we do
叫他们打捞泄洪道
Get them down here and drag the bottom of this spillway.
-为何水还没关掉!  -在进行了
-Why isn't the water turned off? -Somebody from County's working on it.
叫直升机前来支援
Bring in the helicopters now.
我们离开这里
We're out of here!
大概找不出什么东西
I don't think there's anything to find.
还是找找看吧  反正设备都有
Find it anyway. You've got lights and generators coming tonight.
-我不干预你的工作  -直升机停在桥上
-I won't tell you how to do your job... -Put the helicopter on the bridge!
他存活机会很渺茫
but only one person in a million could survive that fall.
可能葬身鱼腹了
The guy is fish food!
那就拿根杆子去捕鱼吧
Get a cane pole. Go catch the fish that ate him.
通知史帝芬  我们要回总部了
Get Stevens. Tell him we're on the way in.
他害得我好惨
That man took everything from me!
我们找不到那家伙
We can't find the guy.
你快去抓他!
You find that man!
你们快去抓他...
发电机及探照灯都装好了
The generators and searchlights are there now.
他们将会彻夜地搜索
They'll continue the search into the night.
很好  打电话谢谢肯塔基警方  以警犬支援我们
Good. Call Kentucky and thank them for the dogs.
记住这出戏还没落幕
Remember, opera ain't over until the Big Dog howls.
要搭便车吗?
Need a ride?
再说一次  要确定无误
Check it again.
发现逃犯踪迹了  他跟一个吸毒的女人住一起
All right, we got him. He shacked up with some babe over in Whiting.
她下班后带他回家
She left work tonight and took him home.
两个小时之前  她老板说的
About two hours ago, her boss said.
在她的住处外发现她的车子
They spotted her car outside her house.
她有跟任何人鬼混吗?
Does she run with anyone?
没有  她也没有家庭
No one we could find. No family either.
叫他们别打草惊蛇
Tell the police not to move till we get there.
我们一早就行动
We'll go first thing in the morning.
你表弟那部卡车还在吧
Your cousin still got his truck?
跟他借用一下
Call him. Tell him we need it.
-装醉  纽曼  -是
-Be drunk, Newman. -Ok
靠近一点
Stay close.
我跟在你屁股后面  老哥
Right on your ass, buddy.
别跟丢了  贴在我身边
I don't want you getting lost. You stick with me.
好
Ok
联邦司法官  全部趴下
U.S. marshals! Everybody down!
别乱动  手伸出来  手举高
Hold it right there! Show me those hands!
举高一点
Keep them up!
滚到那边去
Get your ass in there.
你的人落在我手里  听到了吗
I got your man! I got your man, you hear me?
拜托  别伤到他
Please do not hurt him
我要离开这里
I want out of here!
你们的人落在我手里了
I got your man!
他落在我手里了
我一枪打死他  我要出去
I'm going to blow his brains out! I want out of here!
听到了吧  臭条子
Do you hear me, Cops?
听到了吧
Do you hear me?
我要出去
I want out of here!
-听好  我们商量一下  -我们可以
-Listen! We can work this out! -Yes, we can.
闭嘴...
Shut up! Shut up!
听到了吧
Do you hear me?
我提出我的条件
Listen, and I'll tell you what I want.
我要求一部车子
I just want a car out front.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
别开枪  没事了
It's over.
闭嘴
Shut up!
我几乎听不见了
I can't hear anything. My ear is...
真不相信你下得了手
I can't believe you did that.
你是说  我该跟他谈条件
You think I should've bargained with that guy.
是啊
Yeah.
我是这么认为
I do.
你可能会失手
You could have missed.
害我送命
You could have killed me.
耳朵伤势如何?
How bad is that ear?
很严重  可能会变成聋子
Terrible. I'll have permanent damage.
我瞧瞧
Let me see it.
过来
Come here.
听得到我说的话吗?
Can you hear what I'm saying now?
可以
Yeah.
我绝不...
I don't...
跟人谈条件
...bargain.
听清楚了?
You hear that?
是的
Yeah.
那就好
Good.
华特  我是理查
Walter, this is Richard.
老天  你为什么要逃  现在更难洗刷清白了
Richard, Jesus! Why did you run? Running only makes you look guilty.
这个我不担心
I wasn't worried about appearances, Walter.
你人在哪儿  我陪你去自首
Tell me where you are, so I can meet you and you can surrender.
我不自首  我要向你借点钱
I won't surrender. I need help, money.
理查
Richard
你要我协助一个重刑犯
You're asking me to harbor and aid a convicted felon.
这个我办不到
I can't help you that way.
身为你的好友跟律师  我劝你去自首
My advice both as your friend and legal counselor is to give yourself up.
告诉我  你人在那儿
Now tell me, where are you?
圣路易市
St. Louis.
地址呢? 我马上赶去
Give me an address. I'll get there as soon as I can.
卡普兰是个恶棍  想杀我的部下
Mr. Copeland was a bad man. He was going to kill one of my kids.
那就怪我吧  是我干掉他的
Well, sir, you can blame me. I'm the one that shot him.
我劝你去自首  告诉我  你人在哪儿
Give yourself up. Now tell me, where are you?
圣路易市
St. Louis.
他根本没死  这是你们的教训
So he's not dead. Let that be a lesson to you.
别跟上司争辩  上司永远是对的
Don't ever argue with the Big Dog. Big Dog is always right.
你以前也没错
Yeah, you been right before.
华特  我是理查
Walter, this is Richard.
老天  你为什么要逃  现在更难洗刷清白了
Why did you run? It only makes you look guilty.
这个我不担心
I wasn't worried about appearances.
你人在哪儿  我陪你去自首
Tell me where you are, so I can meet you and you can surrender.
我不自首  我需要钱
I won't surrender. I need help, money.
听起来像火车行驶在高架铁路
I might be crazy, but that train sounds like an El.
圣路易没有高架铁路
St. Louis doesn't have one.
你怎么知道是高架铁路?
How do you know it's an elevated train?
我在高架铁路下住了廿年
I lived under an El for 20 years.
那你解释一下  高架铁路跟地面铁路声音有何不同
Explain the difference between the sound of an El and a train on the ground.
你的耳朵一定很敏锐
You must have ears like an eagle.
再播一次  我要听火车声音
Play that back. I want to hear the sound of an El.
哪些城市有高架铁路  纽约
What cities have Els? New York has got an El.
-费城  -我们芝加哥也有...
-Philly. -We do.Milwaukee has got an El.
停住好像有铃声
Hold it! Where the lawyer says he's guilty. There's a bell in the background.
有男声广播的声音  能把其他杂音去掉吗?
There's a guy on a P.A. Can you drop everything but him?
我试试看
I'll try. Hold on.
华特  我是理查...
Walter I'm Richard
就是这里
Right there.
列车长在说什么?
What's he saying?
听起来像是  下一站  再放一次
Sounds like, "Next stop." Do that again!
"下一站是..."
"Next stop..."
"商品市场"
"Merchandise Mart."
狗东西  他回来了
Son of a bitch! Our boy came home.
那铃声是在华尔街桥  6条街之隔
That bell is on the Wells Street bridge, six blocks away.
我早知道是高架铁路
I knew it was an El.
上司永远是对的
Yeah, Big Dog. You're never wrong.
-我通知芝加哥警局  -这是他的档案
-I'll call the C.P.D. -This is his Chicago file.
出发了
Andiamo, bambini.
山姆  我下辈子想变成你
Sammy, when I die, I want to come back just like you.
过得快乐又长得帅
Happy and handsome?
-我通知新闻界  -不要
-I'll notify the press. -No press.
那就不通知了
Right, no press.
-比利  -你好吗  先生
-Hi, Billy. -How's it going, sir?
-很好  你呢  -还好
-Good, and you? -All right.
-请收下  -回头见
-Here you go, Billy. -Have a good one, sir.
洗车吗  先生
Spare change? Dollar, mister?
不用了
No, thank you
谢谢  不必擦了
No, thank you very much. I don't want it.
不要...
No
是你  理查
Oh, my God. Richard!
你还好吧  查理
How are you, Charlie?
天啊你敢回来
Jesus, you're back.
我需要一些钱
I need some money.
没问题  快进来
Sure, sure. Get in.
不行  身上的掏一点就可以了
No, I can't. Just whatever you got on you.
警方也会盯着你很紧
You're hot, pal. If not now, you will be.
你有住的地方吗? 我怎么找你?
Have you got a place to stay? I mean, how can I help you?
现在是绿灯  快开走
You've got a green light. Move on!
我再跟你连络
I'll call you.
理查...
Charlie
金波为何谋杀妻子?
So why did Richard Kimble kill his wife?
为了钱
He did it for the money.
为了钱? 他是医生早就有钱了
For the money? He's a doctor. He's already rich.
她更有钱
She was more rich.
所有资料就这些?
Is this the entire Chicago Police Department file?
-都在里面了  -我要重新查访一遍
-That's everything. -I want to do all the interviews again.
有医院员工名册吗?
The list of hospital staff is it in the file?
当然
Sure is.
谢了
Thank you.
不想运用新闻媒体?
You don't want to use the media?
不  我们想让他松懈下来  回到以前的生活
We want him to relax. Make himself comfortable. Try to re -enter his life.
就是这一间
Here's the apartment.
有暖气  你不会冻着
You can see here is heater. You will have warm.
厨房水槽
Here is kitchen. Sink.
那边是浴室  这里是卧房
Over there is bathroom. And here is the room.
床很坚固
Is nice bed.
空间很大
Plenty space.
可以四处看看
You can look at.
还满意吗?
So you like the place?
没问题?
It's okay with you?
好得很
It's perfect.
各位
All right, people.
今早接到司法官通知
As this morning we were notified by the U.S. Marshal's Office...
我们的好友金波先生  人还活着
that our old friend Dr. Richard Kimble is alive and well
且回来芝加哥了
and back here in Chicago.
我不敢小看这个杂碎...
You all know in what high regard we hold this scumbag.
特地准备了一瓶陈年好酒...
So I'm personally donating a bottle of 12-year -old Scotch...
送给抓到这位江湖医生的弟兄
...to whoever puts the collar on this quack.
狄克正在分发他的资料
Dick Rosetti is passing out bulletins.
库克郡医院
义肢矫正室
-有何贵干? -我去义肢矫正室
-Help you? -Gracias.
环保部门
荷西狄斯蒙杜
你们是医学院同窗?
You went to medical school together?
没错
Yes, we did.
73年毕业的
The class of '73.
你认识芬柏先生吗?
You know Morton Feinberg?
-是的  -他是个大好人
-I do. -He's a real nice guy.
上次见面是什么时侯?
When did you see him last?
理查吗?
Who, Richard?
今天早上才碰面
I saw Richard this morning.
今天早上?
You saw him this morning?
他拦下我车子  我给他一点钱
He stopped me in my car. I gave him money.
在哪儿碰到的?
Where was this?
我的网球俱乐部外头
Outside my tennis club.
他有求你帮忙?
Did he ask for help?
我自愿帮他  但他不接受
I volunteered. He wouldn't accept that.
你给他多少钱?
How much did you give him?
几块钱  仅仅是我身上的零钱
Couple of bucks. Just what I had on me.
-这点钱跑不远的  -他回来干什么?
-He won't get far on that. -Why'd he come back to Chicago?
他没告诉我
He didn't tell me that, sir.
他一定不会拖你下水  不过...
I'm sure he's trying to protect you from having to lie for him, but...
尼可斯医生
Dr. Nichols
你真的想帮他忙
You really want to be his friend and help him?
那就帮我们逮他回来吧
Help us bring him in unharmed.
为什么?
Why?
要他回来坐牢?
So he can go back to prison?
你们找错人了  我不会干这种事
If you want help, gentlemen, you've come to the wrong man.
理查是清白的
Richard is innocent.
你们也逮不到他  他太聪明了
You'll never find him. He's too smart.
我们也不笨
We're some smart guys.
我们  我们也很聪明  他能有多聪明
What about us? We're smart. We are. How smart could he be, really?
跟你一样聪明?
Is he as smart as you are?
比我更聪明
Smarter.
我是心脏周围血管科专门医生
Peripheral vascular surgery. Fixing the arteries as they come out of the heart.
-你认识金波医生多久了? -10年了
-How long have you known Kimble? -Ten years. Since I've been here.
他的专长是哪个项目?
What kind of medicine did he practice here at the hospital?
我相信  理查是无辜的
I want you to know that I believe Kimble to be innocent.
他会找你帮忙吗?
Would he come to you for help?
他找我的话  我会帮他
If he came to me, I would help.
但他不会找我
But he wouldn't come to me.
这不是他的作风
That's not his style.
悬而未决的手令芝加哥外科医生理查德金波
A warrant remains outstanding for Chicago surgeon, Richard Kimble.
他说独臂人从楼梯摔下来
This is where the one -armed guy he struggled fell down the stairs.
如果是我  一定摔死了
If I fell down these stairs, I'd be a goner. I'd be dead.
真可惜
What a waste!
义肢复健学
我回家时  看到一个陌生人
When I came home, there was a man in my house.
理查...
Richard.
我们是警察
We are the police
他在哪?
Where is he
抓住他...别让他跑了
Grabbed him... Do not let him run
站住看你往哪逃
Stopped and see you where to escape
你想卖毒品给小女孩吗
You like stringing out 12-year -old girls, huh?
你们怎么抓我的宝贝儿子
What are you doing with my baby?
你宝贝儿子是个毒贩
Your baby's a drug dealer, lady.
别这样
Come on, ma'am.
怎么这样对我的宝贝儿子
What they doing to my baby?
今晚有得忙了  死伤多少?
It will be crazy here tonight. Did they get a count?
很多小孩受伤
A lot of kids.
都载来这儿急救
They bring them all here?
都载到这儿来了
All coming down here to County.
我来清扫窗帘
I've come to do those blinds.
好的  我来关门
I'll get the door.
从这儿开始?
I'll start in here, huh?
可以
Ok
男性30至50岁  右臂
更换部位  上节肢
上次矫正
1月21日至2月1日
符合资料者  21人
义肢模型  混合式
符合资料者  5人
打印
我们再核对一次
Let's go over it once more.
他何时抵达这栋房子?
What time did he arrive at the house?
约上午10点半
About 10:30 in the morning.
-他单独一人? -是的
-And he was alone? -Yeah, he was alone.
-你看清楚他的容貌吗? -很清楚
-You got a good look at him? -Yeah, a real good look.
你别耍花样
You better be straight with me.
住在你母亲房子的就是此人?
This is the guy staying in your mother's basement?
我说的就是他
That's what I'm telling you.
深呼吸  放轻松
Take a deep breath relax
找个医生来帮忙
I need a doctor over here!
小心
Watch the bag! Watch the bag!
通知小孩的父母
Notify the parents of young children
谢谢医生
Thanks Doctors
好痛
It really hurts
司法官  就是那儿没错
Hello, Marshal. It's right there.
我的胸部很痛
My chest hurts.
验一下那小孩的X光片
Check the film on that kid.
深呼吸一下
Take a deep breath.
吸气  呼气
Inhale, exhale. Again.
慢慢地
Slowly.
验X光片
Check the film.
放轻松
Take it easy.
验X光片
X -ray inspection
小孩的情况如何?
What's the status on that kid?
可能是胸骨断裂
Possible fractured sternum.
来帮个忙  挪个位子出来  还有伤患
Get over here. I need you.
帮个忙  把孩子送到观察室
Can you help us? Bring this kid to Observation Room Two.
就是你  帮帮忙好吗?
Yeah, you. Come on, help us out, okay?
你还好吧?
How are you, champ?
我胸部会痛
My chest hurts.
呼吸时会痛吗?
Does it hurt when you breathe?
是的
Yes.
-你叫什么名字? -乔
-What's your name? -Joel.
瞧这个
Look at this.
好家伙  竟然伪造身份证
We're eating oranges and we're making IDs.
C.C.H.代表什么?
"C.C.H." What the hell is that?
库克郡医院
Cook County Hospital.
忍耐一点  好吗?
Just hang on, okay?
你没事  老弟
You'll be just fine.
不会有事
Nothing
停一下
Hold that elevator.
谢谢
Thank you.
情况如何
How about?
胸部会痛
My chest hurts.
你母亲呢?
Where's your mom, pal?
我不知道
I don't know.
她在家里吗?
Is she at home?
可能跟哥哥在一起
I think she's with my brother.
他们在楼下吗?
Your brother? They're downstairs?
我不知道
I don't know.
别担心
Don't worry.
我们会找到她
We'll find her for you.
你玩橄榄球  棒球吗?
What are you? Football player? Baseball player?
橄榄球
Football.
撑着点  老弟
Hold on, son.
嘿  医生
Hey, Doctor.
楼下送来这个
They sent this one from downstairs.
送到4号房快点
Get this one into Room Four, stat.
再见  乔
Bye-bye, Joel.
我送来的那个小孩呢?
Where's that boy I sent here?
-什么小孩? -胸骨断裂的那个
-What boy? -The one with the fractured sternum.
没看到
He never came through here.
-没看到? -没有
-He didn't? -No, he didn't.
你对那X光片感兴趣?
Do you have a particular interest in our patient's X -rays?
-什么意思? -我瞧见你在看他的X光片
-What do you mean? -I saw you looking at that boy's chest film.
-个人的小嗜好  -小嗜好  真的吗?
-It's a hobby of mine. -It's a hobby, really?
你还有其他嗜好吗? 脑部手术?
What's your other hobby, brain surgery?
-你想怎样? -小孩为何送入手术房?
-What do you want? -To know how that boy got to surgery.
我是清洁工  听命行事
I'm a janitor. I do as I'm told.
狗屎
That's bullshit!
是谁删改病历?
Who changed those orders?
我不懂你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
你别走
You stay right there.
叫警卫来
Call Security!
借过
Please
通知史帝芬...找芝加哥警局的凯利...
Tell Stevens to get hold of that guy Kelly over at C.P.D.
有人装扮成清洁工  并下令动紧急手术
A guy disguised as a janitor orders an emergency medical procedure...
而你只扣下他的证件
...and all you did was take away his I.D. card?
我一叫警卫他就溜了  我还能怎样
No, I called Security. He took off down the hall. What was I supposed to do?
听着  你是...
Listen, Mr...
副司法官
Deputy.
吉拉
Gerard.
我累了
I'm really tired.
想回家
I'd like to go home now.
好吧  小孩情况如何?
Okay. How's the boy doing?
他救了他一命
He saved his life
谢谢
Thank you.
狄斯蒙杜鲁斯
"Desmondo, Jose Ruiz."
狄斯蒙杜  你在那里
Where're you at, Desmondo?
山姆  有一点我搞不懂
Okay, Sam, this is my problem.
这里四处都是警察  对吧?
The place is crawling with cops, right?
每一个都在追查金波  对吧?
Everybody's looking for Richard Kimble, right?
那他为什么笨得
So why would a guy be stupid enough...
跑来这里扮演大善人?
...to hang out in the trauma ward and play Mother Teresa?
借过
Excuse me.
有事吗?
You, guys, have a problem?
没什么事
No, no. No problem at all.
打扰  跟你聊几句好吗
Excuse me, could we have a word with you, please?
我是库克郡医院的艾威医生
This is Dr. Elway at Cook County Hospital.
我在为义肢部门  追踪齐力克先生目前的情况
I'm following-up for the prosthetic clinic on Matthew Zelick.
真的?
Oh, he did?
我很遗憾
I'm terribly sorry.
右臂或左臂?
Right or left?
右臂
Right.
-年纪? -35到45
-Age? -35 to 45.
我是高中同学会的里莱
This is Ted Riley with the High School Reunion Committee.
毕业25周年纪念来临了
25 years are right around the corner...
一直没有克莱夫的消息...
...and Clive is on our list of missing in action.
查号台给我这个号码  但我...
The information gave me a number, but when I tried it...
不是开玩笑?
No kidding.
持枪抢劫?
Armed robbery?
他关在哪儿?
He's where?
义肢安装部位?
Point of attachments?
上臂的中部
Mid -humerus.
那么  有嫌疑的共47位
That gives us 47 possibles.
47位!
47?
再对照他们的犯罪纪录
Cross -check these people for criminal records.
马上就好
Wait a minute.
快乐圣帕特里克节给大家
Happy St. Patrick's Day to all of you.
你好吗?
How are you?
你好
How are you
克莱夫狄瑞斯可先生
Driscoll, Clive R.
独臂人  持枪抢劫  真有意思...
One -armed man, armed robbery. That's funny.
有个问题
Question:
如果今天能把河水染成绿色
If they can dye this river green today...
为何不能在剩下的364天里染成蓝色?
...why can't they dye it blue the other days?
我怎么知道
How do I know?
-你是爱尔兰人吗? -谁  我吗
-So, what are you Irish, sir? -Who, me? No.
不是
No
你是爱尔兰人吗?
Are you?
我不是
No, man!
犯人姓名
Name of inmate?
狄瑞斯可克莱夫
Clive Driscoll.
Driscoll, Clive.
证件
I.D., please.
狄瑞斯可
Driscoll, Clive R.
2-0-1-0
照法庭规定
Be advised that under federal court ruling,
你们的对话可能会被录音
your conversation can be recorded.
请签名
Sign here, please!
这很怪诞  金波聪明得很
This is hinky. He is a college graduate.
应该不会来此自投罗网
He wouldn't go through all this security go to the county lock -up
来监狱找一个可能不存在的人
to find someone his own people say doesn't exist.
怪诞
Hinky.
"怪诞"是什么意思?
What does that mean, "hinky"?
-奇怪的  -陌生的
-Strange. -Weird.
说"奇怪"或"不可思议"  "怪诞"没有任何意义
Say "strange" or "weird". "Hinky" has no meaning.
"怪诞"  没什么意义
Why not say "hinky"?
"怪诞"  有什么不对?
"Hinky" What is wrong?
我不想听没意义的字眼  我走楼梯好了
I don't want you using meaningless words around me. I'm taking the stairs.
狗屎
bullshit!
"狗屎"  有意义吗?
How about "bullshit"?
狄瑞斯可的访客
Visitor for Driscoll.
我们走吧
Come on, let's go, let's go.
那边请坐
Over there.
走吧  狄瑞斯可
Let's go, Driscoll.
会面时间5分钟
You've got five minutes.
你是哪位?
Who the hell are you?
对不起  我弄错了
Look, I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
都叫我出来了
You got me down here...
好歹也要聊两句
...might as well talk.
牢里闷得很  又没闭路电视
Down here you got no entertainment. Ain't no cable here.
我不能跟你多聊  抱歉
Listen, pal, I wish I could, but I can't. Sorry.
理查
Richard!
警察先生  穿蓝色外衣的人拿着一把枪对一个女人大吼
There is a man in a blue coat waving a gun and screaming...at a woman.
拦住他
Stop that man!
他是司法官  放开他
He's a U.S. marshal! Let him go! Let him go!
门关上
Close the gates!
站住
Hold it!
门打开
Open the doors!
我们在屋顶
We're on the roof.
找几个人  看看那边
Take some men! Look down there!
他进入广场了
Jesus, he's in the plaza, Sam!
朝东边逃逸
He's heading east!
朝东走正接近毕加索的雕像
He's going east toward the Picasso!
庆祝"圣·帕特里克"节日
Happy St. Patrick's Day to all of you.
吉拉先生  你认为金波医生回来的目的是什么?
Deputy Gerard, why do you feel that Dr. Kimble came back to Chicago?
我不知道
I have no idea.
你的属下今天曾前往医院
We understand your deputies were at the hospital today.
金波去过那儿吗?
Was Dr. Kimble at the hospital?
无可奉告
I don't have any comment on that one.
我把案发经过再重复一遍
Let me get the chronology straight.
他被审判  定罪  入狱...
The subject was tried, convicted, incarcerated...
脱逃  一度被假设死亡
...escaped, presumed dead,
现在又返回芝加哥  对吧?
and is now at large in Chicago. Is that correct, sir?
我们未曾假设他死亡
Except for being presumed dead.
他持械逃亡  是个危险人物?
Do you believe that Kimble's armed and dangerous?
我认为他是危险人物
I believe he's dangerous, yes.
他既然冒险返回本市
He's taking chances, coming back.
你会认为他是清白的吗?
Do you feel that perhaps he might be innocent?
他不是清白的  他被法院判刑
No, he's not innocent. He was convicted in a court of law. He's guilty.
他有罪  你准备怎么样抓他?
How will you try to catch him?
恕不奉告了  各位
We have no further comments for now.
旅馆  限男客
杰出员工奖  塞克斯
艾立克
Alec.
理查·金波
Richard Kimble.
-你好  -金波医师
-Hi, how are you? -Good, Dr. Kimble.
蓝兹
Lentz!
我们查了最近的电话记录...
Sorry, we've been trading phone calls the last few days.
德弗林·迈格瑞格制药厂
德弗林·迈格瑞格儿童疾病研究基金会
制药厂主办的旅游可能会很好玩
A cruise sponsored by Devlin MacGregor...that could be fun.
祝愉快
I wish a happy
-墨西哥坎康岛  -度假钓鱼
-Cancun, Richard. -Sport fishing.
享受墨西哥鸡尾酒
Pina coladas.
那我们是不是得向你们买药?
What must the hospital buy? What's the catch?
放心度假钓鱼去吧
Sailfish.
制药厂没有别的意思
No, there are no strings attached.
你意下如何  你意下如何...
So what do you say? So what do you say?
这个人连毛细孔都流血了
This guy is bleeding from every needle puncture.
蓝兹的病人  他服了那种奇迹的药?
Lentz sent this guy in? Is he on that wonder drug?
是的  他在试用RDU-90  万能之药
Yes, he's on the RDU -90 protocol, Provasic.
未来世界的药物
Drug of the future, boys.
能打通血管  还能让我们全部失业
Clean out those arteries and put us out of business.
游行主办人欧佛拉提说...
"Parade Master of Ceremonies Ed O'Flaherty said...
这是20年来最精采的一次游行
"...he didn't recall a livelier parade during the last 20 years.
听着...
"That Kimble...
"金波是个不得了的小伙子"
"...is some kind of lad..."
-"小伙子? "  -他是这么说的
-"Lad? " -Yeah, "lad."
也许他是个小矮人  我是照报纸上说的
Maybe he's a leprechaun. I'm quoting this guy.
3线电话上有人自称是金波
Some guy on line three claims he's Richard Kimble.
-是谁? -又有人自称是金波
-Who is it? -We got another Kimble on line three.
话筒给我
Let me see that phone.
跟他说  他留胡子很帅
Tell him he looks good in a beard.
-哪一线电话? -3线
-What line? -Three.
"我希望他能穿绿色衣服..."
"l hope he was able to wear a little green, sip some whiskey..."
我是吉拉
This is Gerard.
记得我在隧道内跟你说的话?
Do you remember what I told you in the tunnel?
是他没错
It's him!
我记得...当时里面很吵
I remember it was noisy.
你好像说过...
Well, I think you said something like...
你妻子不是你杀的
...you didn't kill your wife.
记得你对我说什么吗?
Remember what you told me?
我记得你拿枪对着我
I remember you were pointing my gun at me.
你说"我不在乎"
You said, "I don't care."
他在南区
He's on the south side.
没错  我不在乎
Yeah, Richard, that's right, I don't care.
我不是在玩解谜游戏
I'm not trying to solve a puzzle, here.
我倒是在解一个谜
Well, I am trying to solve a puzzle.
再5秒就可追踪到
Five seconds to location.
我刚刚找到一个大的部分
And I just found a big piece.
理查
Richard?
理查...
哈罗  理查
Hello, Richard?
他没挂掉电话
He didn't hang up the phone.
在哪儿打的?
Where is he?
圣劳伦斯南路  256号
256 South St. Lawrence.
叫芝城警局的人来
Get the C.P.D. right the hell over there.
我们的人现在正在那儿
We got a car there now.
这里拍几张
Get a couple of shots of that.
雷德瑞塞克斯
Fredrick Sykes...
45岁  曾担任警察  衣服还真不少
...45, ex-cop, and quite a clotheshorse.
看看这个...
You want to look at this?
金波的指纹  到处都是
Kimble's prints. They're all over...
尤其是桌子上
...but mainly on the desk.
他对这些照片很感兴趣
He sure had some interest in these photographs.
有负片吗?
Negatives in there?
给我
Let me have them.
-我们等的人来了  -听到了
-Camera boy's on his way. -We got you.
你好  塞克斯先生
How're you doing, Mr. Sykes?
-发生了什么事? -有点小问题
-Fine, if you tell me what's happening. -We had a problem.
-我的住处  或是楼上  -你的住处
-My place or the place upstairs? -Your place.
请进去吧
Step right in, Mr. Sykes.
大家都知道我的名字  我们好像一家人
Everybody knows my name here. Big happy family, huh?
搞什么  开侦探大会  搞什么名堂
What is this, a trench coat convention? What the hell is going on?
你们是谁  在干什么?
Who are you guys? What's going on?
你家被闯空门了
You had a break -in, Mr. Sykes.
希望你是条子没错
I sure hope you're a cop.
我是吉拉  司法官办公室的
No, I'm Samuel Gerard, United States Marshal's Office.
今早有一位叫金波的逃犯  在这儿打了一通电话
This morning a fugitive named Richard Kimble made a phone call from here.
他的目的你知道吗?
Why would he do that?
我不认识叫什么金波的
I don't know any Richard Kimble.
我想起来了
Okay, I got it.
是那个杀死妻子的医生  对吧
The doctor who killed his wife, right?
把罪名推给一个装义肢的  他想陷害我吗?
Keep blaming somebody with a prosthetic limb. Is he coming after me?
他有理由这样做吗?
Does he have reason to do so?
我装了义肢  那一定是我干的喽
I have a prosthetic arm! I must've done it!
饶了我吧  一年前就问过我了
Give me a break. I went through all this a year ago.
就在这里被警方彻底讯问
I was questioned here about the whole thing.
我说  案发当晚我不在芝加哥  我有事出城去了
I told them I wasn't in Chicago on that night. I was on business trip.
有15个人替我作证
15 people verified it.
你干哪一行的?
What line of business are you in?
保安
Security.
-你替谁工作? -一家制药厂
-Who do you work for? -A pharmaceutical company.
哪一家?
Which one?
德弗林·迈格瑞格  我负责高级主管的安全
Devlin MacGregor. I handle security for all the top executives.
金波为何对这些照片感兴趣?
Do you have any idea why Kimble would be interested in these photographs?
不知道
No.
在哪儿拍的?
Where were they taken?
真是条大鱼
Gee, that's a big fish!
在墨西哥坎康拍的
Cancun, Mexico.
药厂免费招待一些医生旅游
It was a junket the company paid for some doctors.
-金波也去了? -照片里没有他吧!
-Kimble go with you? -You don't see him there, do you?
我说过  我不认识他!
No. I told you I don't know him.
我看看财物有无失窃  行不行?
Do you mind if I look around to see if anything's missing?
请便
No, I don't mind.
你手臂怎么断的?
How'd you lose that arm?
执勤时弄断的
In the line of duty.
这家伙有点嫌疑
Cosmo, this guy's dirty.
是有嫌疑
Yes, he is.
-要找人盯他吗? -是的  在这儿布下盯哨
-You want our people on him? -Yes. Build a camp here.
我来处理
I'll take care of it.
看这张照片  查查塞克斯旁边那个人
See this picture? I want you to find out who's the guy next to Sykes.
姓名  年龄  体重  保险卡号码
Find out his name, his age, his weight, his social security number...
住处  亲人  宠物  通通查
...his location, relatives, pets, everything.
芝加哥希尔顿酒店  欢迎国际心脏医学协会
对不起  他们说有急事
I am so sorry, Doctor, they said it was an emergency.
失陪
Thank you. Excuse me.
波顿先生
Mr. Bolton.
查理
Chuck.
理查
Richard.
方便讲话吗
Convenience of the floor?
没问题  这是旅馆电话  你还好吧  事情如何了?
Yes, I'm on a hotel phone. So how are you? What's going on?
我找到杀死海伦的凶手了
I found him, Chuck. I found the man who killed Helen.
什么?
What?
他们其实是想干掉我
lt was me they were after.
他们是谁?
Who are they?
德弗林·迈格瑞格  还有蓝兹
Devlin MacGregor and Lentz.
蓝兹负责RDU-90试验
Lentz was supervising the protocol for RDU-90.
而我发现了此药会损害肝脏  就是他没错
He knew I found out it was causing liver damage. It was Lentz.
理查  蓝兹早就死了
Richard, Lentz is dead.
什么...怎么死的?
What? How?
去年夏天出车祸死的
He died in a car accident last summer.
理查
Richard.
药物的事情你能证明吗?
Can you prove this about the drug?
我想可以
Yeah, I think so.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help, Chuck.
打电话给医院的邦斯  请他协助我
Call Bones at the hospital. Tell him to give me whatever help I need.
我马上通知他
I'll call him now.
好  多谢
Okay. Thanks.
尼可斯医生
Dr. Nichols!
你好
How are you?
尼可斯医生
Dr. Nichols!
能请教几个问题吗?
Can we ask you a few more questions?
吉拉先生
Mr. Gerard.
照片带了没?
You got a copy of that photograph?
司法官办公室
U.S. Marshal Service.
失陪一下
Excuse us.
尼可斯医生  这是塞克斯
This is Fredrick Sykes.
他是迈格瑞格药厂的安全人员
He's a security specialist at Devlin MacGregor Pharmaceuticals.
金波偷闯他的公寓
Richard Kimble broke into his apartment.
此人你认识吗?
Do you know this man?
不认识
No, I don't know him.
你有些绝望了  不是吗?
You're getting pretty desperate, aren't you, Mr. Gerard?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我说过  你抓不到理查
I told you, you wouldn't find Richard.
-他找过你吗? -没有
-Has he been to see you? -No.
这件事我们不是讨论过了吗
We've been over this ground before, haven't we?
-我不奉陪了  -请便
-So, if you'll excuse me. -Sure.
-谢了  -谢谢  医生
-Thanks, Doc. -Thank you, Doctor.
对不起  再问个问题
Sorry, I want to ask you one more question about the photograph.
鱼右边  穿紫色衬衫的那个人
See the guy standing on the right side of the fish?
你见过吗?
Ever see him before?
没有
No
就是这个人
This guy right here?
我一生中从未见过这个人
I've never seen that person in my life before.
-好了  -对不起
-Okay. -I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢  医生  祝您开会愉快
Thank you, Doctor. Enjoy the rest of the convention.
替代性药物  清除血管壁沉积物的治疗法
"Alternatives to Cardio-Non-Invasive Arterial Plaque-Reducing Therapy.
主讲人  尼可斯医生
"Keynote speaker, Charles Nichols."
这种题目保证卖座
Bet they line up to hear this one.
如果你是金波的话
If you were Richard Kimble...
为何要追踪那位独臂人
...why would you hunt for a one-armed man you say killed your wife...
闯入他的住处  打电话给我们  然后再溜掉
...break into his house, call us up and then split?
我该改行当医生
I should have been a doctor.
看看放大后的照片  塞克斯旁边那个人的上衣
Look at this blow-up. This guy in the picture with Sykes. On his shirt.
芝加哥纪念医院
Chicago Memorial.
是金波工作的医院  我去看看
I want to go there.
去吧
Go!
等一下
Wait.
德弗林·迈格瑞格...
Devlin MacGregor...
去年一年的净收入...达75亿美元
...did 7.5 billion dollars in net sales...last year alone.
这家公司庞大的吓人
That company is a monster.
有话快说...
Yeah, talk to me.
绝对如此
Absolutely.
我要找的是肝部组织样本
It's a liver sample...
RDU-90人体实验的样本
...from a patient on the RDU-90 drug study.
1月21日
21. January 21st?
啊最后一件
The last one!
1-7-4-3-0
1-7-4-3-0?
1-7-4-3-0  没错
1-7-4-3-0. You got it.
谢了  这些资料会还给你
Thanks. I'll make sure all this stuff gets back to you.
-很高兴见到你  -我也是
-It's good to see you again. -Good to see you.
你太太那件案子进行如何?
So whatever happened to that thing with your wife?
还没结束
It's not over yet.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
我怎么知道
How should I know?
他是艾立克·蓝兹  病理学家
I think his name is Lentz. A pathologist.
我记得他去年夏天刚过世
I remember because he died last summer.
我的天  理查
Oh, my God. Richard!
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
嗨  凯撒琳
Hi, Kath.
瞧瞧这个
Have a look.
-你看到什么? -正常人体组织
-What do you think? -Cold normal.
显然不是原来的组织样本
Clearly not the same tissue.
不但都是正常的肝脏
And not only did they all come from healthy livers...
而且是同一片肝脏切下来的
...they all came from the same liver.
干得好
Kath, you beauty.
打扰
Excuse me.
你是罗斯福先生?
Mr. Roosevelt?
我们两人是副司法官
I am Deputy Biggs, this is Deputy Newman. We're U.S. marshals.
想要一点有关蓝兹的资料
Need some information about a Dr. Lentz who was on staff here.
蓝兹认识金波医生吗?
I want to know if he knew or have had any contact with a Dr. Richard Kimble?
我没见过金波医生
I haven't seen Dr. Kimble.
你答非所问
I didn't ask that.
我反正不晓得
I wouldn't know.
失陪了  我还有急事要处理
If you'll excuse me, I have prior obligations to attend to.
-罗斯福先生  -请说
-Mr. Roosevelt -please say
你在撒谎
I think you're lying to us.
蓝兹是元凶?
You think Lentz is the bad guy?
为何不是呢
Yeah, why not?
他有RDU-90的专利权
He was one of the original patent boys in RDU-90.
我正要把检验样本送出去
I was sending in my tissue samples...
他用正常的样本加以调包后  再签发合格报告书
...he was replacing them with healthy samples, issuing the path reports...
我的样本被他丢了
...shit -canning my stuff. Easy.
等等
Wait a minute.
蓝兹死于8月21日
Lentz died August 21st.
有一半的合格书...  是在这一天签署的
Half the samples he approved were signed the day he died.
你没开玩笑?
You're kidding.
一定还有其他人在搞鬼
Someone else must have been manipulating this.
内部的人搞的
Someone with access.
多谢了
Thanks, Kath.
你上哪儿?
Where're you going?
去拜访一位好友
To see a friend.
这个案子令我头痛
This is giving me a headache.
很怪  罗斯福说金波去哪里?
That's surprising. Where did Roosevelt say Kimble was going?
他说不知道
He says he doesn't know.
-你相信他的话  -是的
-Do you believe him? -Yes, I do.
他说金波去找组织样本
He says he was here to pick up some tissue samples...
研究药物用的样本
...for a drug study.
听听这个
But listen, get this.
样本是经过尼可斯批准的
The release was approved by Dr. Charles Nichols.
尼可斯也认识蓝兹
Nichols also knew Lentz.
他是蓝兹的上司
He was Lentz's boss.
他一定隐瞒了有关金波的事
He was covering for Kimble.
快通知芝加哥警方去医院
Send the C.P.D. over there right now.
我们将派许多警察过去
We're going to send a bunch of cops.
让他们彻底搜查一番
Make sure they turn that place inside out.
别让他们说你的辫子  你干得漂亮
Don't let them give you shit about your ponytail either. Well done.
是我的荣幸
My pleasure, Sam.
亨利
Henry
尼可斯医生骗我
Dr. Nichols lied to me.
-去找他  -我马上去
-Go find him. -I'm on it.
他走了
He's gone by now.
我四处找遍了  没找到他
I looked every place you told me to look and I didn't see him.
我打电话给你
I'm telling you.
如果他在医院  我一定找得到
If he was in the hospital, I would have found him.
你要我怎么做?
So what do you want me to do?
等一下
Hold on. Wait a minute.
我发现他了
I marked him. I got him now.
蓝兹医生
Dr. Alexander Lentz.
芝加哥纪念医院的名医
"A noted pathologist at Chicago Memorial Hospital...
前往网球场途中
"...was walking to his daily tennis match when an unidentified vehicle...
被一不明车辆撞倒
"...slammed his body...
死于湖与公路之间的围墙边
"...into the barriers that separate the Drive from Lake Michigan."
这个令人难以相信
Sam, you're not going to believe this.
塞克斯在这两年来  未曾打电话给金波
Sykes' records for the past two years show no calls to Kimble.
想必如此
It was a thought.
不过  金波的电话纪录上  却打过一通给塞克斯
But when I cross -checked Kimble's phone records, one came up.
金波打电话给塞克斯...
Kimble called Sykes...
找塞克斯来问话
Get Sykes in here now.
谋杀案当晚
...on the night of the murder...
晚上7点30分
...7:30 PM...
从车上行动电话打的
...from his car phone.
有没有金波的警局笔录
Do you have the arrest report on Kimble?
-晚上7点30-19点30分
-7:30 PM. -19:30 hours.19:30
警员刚进去  塞克斯不见了  没法找到他
They just went in. Sykes is gone.
什么?
He's now here to be found.
他溜走了
He's gone.
金波潜伏芝加哥
23组报告
23 Group's report
在艾尔街北向发现金波...
Possible sighting of Richard Kimble on northbound El coming into Van Buren.
到门旁边去  医生
Move to the door, Doc.
下一站巴波瓦街
Next Babo Wa Street
我要下车了
This is my stop.
我也是
This is my stop too.
金波
Richard Kimble
你过站了
You missed your stop.
车子怎么停在那边?
How the car parked in there?
山姆
Sam
列车警察发现金波
A transit cop spotted Kimble on the El, he is heading toward Balbo.
朝巴波瓦街行驶
The C.P.D. is on the way.
芝加哥警局派人去了
Chicago Police Department sent to the
各单位注意  在巴波瓦街站有警员遭枪击
Attention all units. Transit police report officer down at Balbo Station.
嫌疑是金波  重复  警员遭枪击
Kimble is suspect. Repeat officer down.
他做了什么事  枪杀警员?
What'd he do, shoot a cop?
芝加哥警方会生吞了他
Chicago P.D. will eat him alive.
本人很荣幸  介绍今晚的主讲人...
It is a joy and a privilege... to introduce tonight's keynote speaker.
这4年来
For the past four years...
他是罗宾逊基金会的研究人员
...he has served as the A. Jude Robinson Fellow...
及芝加哥纪念医院
...and Administrative Chief of Pathology...
病理部行政主管
...at Chicago Memorial Hospital.
紧急出口在哪儿?
Where are the emergency exits?
嫌犯进入希尔顿酒店的底层
Suspect seen entering Hilton Tower Mall, lower level.
重复  嫌犯进入希尔顿酒店...
Repeat...
你会不会认为...
You don't think...
我知道他要去哪里
I know where he's going.
比克斯  纽曼  你们的位置?
Biggs, Newman, where are you?
最近  他又被任命为...
He was appointed to the Board of Directors...
德弗林·迈格瑞格的主管
...of Devlin MacGregor Pharmaceuticals.
请大家热烈欢迎
You all please give a warm welcome...
查尔斯·尼可斯医生
...to Dr. Charles Nichols.
谢谢  各位先生女士
Thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen...
至友及同事们
...my friends and colleagues.
很高兴今晚在此聚会
It's great you're all here tonight.
警方报告  有警员遭枪击  嫌犯拿两把枪离开现场
C.P.D. reported an officer down and a guy with two guns...
-金波干的? -各种说法都有
-Kimble do it? -Conflicting reports.
他从地下道进入饭店
He entered the hotel from the subway.
-他是我的犯人  -现在不是了
-That's my man! -Not anymore.
警局会捉拿他  请你别插手
He's going down. You can help by staying out.
有种扣押我们
Arrest us!
所有出口都封锁起来
Lock it up! Start at the lower level.
下层封锁完毕之后报告上来
All units report when lower level is secure.
所有单位  封锁所有的安全出口
All units, secure all lower level exits.
找饭店的保卫室  用无线电保持联系
Go and find the hotel security office. Stay in touch with me on the radio.
目前  有一种新药...
Now, a new drug...
即将获得联邦药品局通过
...on the cusp of approval by the Food and Drug Administration...
能彻底改变旧的治疗方法
...is poised to change these old methods forever.
副司法官纽曼
Deputy Newman, U.S. Marshal's Service.
你好
Holle
山姆  我进来了
Sam, I'm in.
以肝部正常新陈代谢的方式
...through the normal metabolic pathways in the liver.
这种新药的名称是...
The drug's name is...
万能之药
...Provasic.
今晚我会为各位介绍
As I will show you tonight...
万能之药的惊人疗效
...Provasic is remarkably effective...
绝对没有副作用
...and has no side effects whatsoever.
要提醒各位  这种药...
It is also noteworthy that this drug...
这种药是经由...
...that this drug was developed...
芝加哥纪念医院的鼎力合作
...in cooperation, not competition with Chicago Memorial Hospital...
我们希望...
...in what we hope will be...
会成为不诚实的...
...the model for a continued dishonest...
对不起  是会成为诚实...
...excuse me, honest...
公开合资发展的典范
...open joint venture...
在医学界...
...between academic medicine...
与制药工业界...理查
...and the pharmaceutical industry...
理查
Richard!
对不起  我正在演讲
I'm sorry, I'm in the middle of this speech.
你的诡计差一点就成功了
You almost got away with it.
我都查清楚了
I know all about it.
我手上有证据
I can prove it.
各位  我的朋友金波有点儿不舒服
Ladies and gentlemen, my friend Richard Kimble doesn't feel well...
这很显然...
...obviously...
请先享用餐点
...so if you just go on with your dessert and coffee...
理查  到一旁谈谈好吗?
Richard, would you step aside and let's talk.
我马上回来
So I'll be back in just a second.
你把样品调包了  对吧
You changed the samples, didn't you?
你在蓝兹死后
You switched the samples...
把样本调包
...after Lentz died.
各位请冷静
Let's stay calm, people.
蓝兹死后  只有你才有权限
After Lentz died, you were the only one who had access.
你把样本对调
You switched the samples...
还有报告书
...and the pathology reports.
你也害死蓝兹
You killed Lentz too?
叫警卫来
Call Security.
都是你干的
Did you?
他伪造研究报告
He falsified his research...
才使RDU-90获得通过
...so RDU-90 could be...approved and...
迈格瑞格才能推出这种新药
..Devlin MacGregor could give you Provasic.
各位  没事了
All right, it's all over, folks.
保持冷静
Let's just stay calm.
你从未放弃  是吗? 你从未放弃!
You never give up, Richard, do you? You never give up!
为什么要杀海伦?
Why Helen?
你们终于来了
Glad you're here.
他们往哪儿去了?
Which way'd they go?
-朝总统套房方向去  -那是哪里啊?
-Toward the Presidential Suite. -Where's that?
-东南方向  -这个房间出口有几个?
-Southeast corner. -How many exits are there in this room?
4个  东西边各两个
We got a total of four: Two on the east, two on the west.
金波在屋顶上
Kimble's on the roof!
柯斯莫  朝那个方向
Cosmo, that way.
别动  站住
Stop! Stay where you are!
这是芝加哥警局
This is the Chicago police!
手举起来
Put your hands in the air!
整座大楼都封锁了
The building is totally secure.
重复一次  不要动
I repeat, do not move!
手举起来
Put your hands in the air!
重复一次  站着别动
I repeat, stay where you are!
报告目前情况
Talk to me.
他们在屋顶上朝北边跑
They're headed to the north end of the roof.
纽曼
Newman!
叫直升机离开
Get that helicopter out of here!
只要一发现他  格杀勿论
As soon as you get a clean shot...you take him out.
叫直升机离开
Newman, get rid of the helicopter!
-为什么? -我不想挨子弹
-Why? -Because I don't want to get shot!
芝加哥警局  屋顶上有司法官  立即停火
C.P.D., there's a U.S. marshal out on the roof. Hold your fire!
叫直升机离开
Call off the helicopter!
山姆
sam
别开枪
Don't shoot.
这家伙永远不放弃
This guy ever quit?
看看电梯停在哪儿?
Find out where that elevator stops.
纽曼
Newman
西北方的电梯会停在哪儿?
Northwest elevator! Where does it stop?
他们人呢...
Where did they go?
-停在五楼  -他们在五楼
-Stopped on the 5th floor. -They're on the 5th floor.
-五楼有什么? -洗衣部
-What's on the 5th floor? -It's the laundry.
他们在洗衣部
They stopped at the laundry.
我们在五楼  你们位置呢?
We're on the 5th floor. What's your 20?
就在你们后方
It's right behind you.
这里怎么回事?
What the hell is going on here?
叫芝加哥警方别插手  他们会乱开火
You got to keep the C.P.D. out. They're much too hot to suit me.
叫他们离开
I want you to get rid of all these people.
大家都听到了  请冷静
Okay, people, stay calm.
柯斯莫  跟我来
Cosmo, come with me.
请各位迅速离开
Please leave quickly
理查·金波医生
Dr. Richard Kimble!
你已经插翅难飞了  理查
There's no way out of here, Richard!
整栋大楼都被封锁了
The entire building is locked down!
投降吧  你时间不多了
Give it up, you don't have any time!
芝加哥警方怀疑你枪杀警员
Chicago Police Department thinks you're a cop killer!
他们会当场毙掉你
They will shoot you on sight!
我知道你是清白的
Richard, I know you're innocent!
我知道塞克斯的事
I know about Fredrick Sykes!
也知道尼可斯医生在搞鬼
I know about Dr. Charles Nichols!
案发当晚他借用你的车子
Richard, he borrowed your car the night of your wife's murder!
所以他有你家的钥匙
He had the keys!
不必破门而入
No forced entry, Richard.
他用你车上电话连络塞克斯
He telephoned Sykes from your car, Richard!
别追他了
Give it up!
你再不投降我只好开枪杀你了
I'm either lying to you or I'm going to shoot you!
你要想清楚
What do you think?
别追他了  该停下来了
Give it up! It's time to stop running!
他们杀害了我的妻子
They killed my wife.
我知道  理查
I know it, Richard.
我知道了
I know it.
事情结束了
But, it's over now.
我很高兴
You know, I'm glad.
我要好好休息一阵
I need the rest.
是谁杀死金波的夫人?
Who killed Kimble's wife?
被定罪的是金波
Kimble was convicted of it.
金波说是独臂人干的  你们抓到一个独臂人
You've got a one -armed man in custody.
-就是他吗? -我不知道
-Is that the guy? -I have no idea.
到底有多少个独臂人?
How many one-armed men are there?
有很多个?
There're a lot of them.
你是否抓错人了...
Could you have made a mistake?
独臂人抓到了
Armed man captured
我从未办过这么复杂的案子
I have never worked on so complex case
你截稿时间到了
You got a deadline, play the weather again.
抓错人了吗?
Arrested the wrong person it?
告诉吉拉  我要请假  我要度假去了
Tell Samuel Gerard I'm going home now. I'm taking my vacation.
清理现场快点清理
Clear this area. Everybody clear.
金波医生...
Kimble
脑袋别碰到
Watch your head.
到底怎么一回事...
How about the thing
钥匙在哪儿呢?
Where is that key?
手伸出来  医生
Let me see those hands, Doctor.
我以为你不在乎
I thought you didn't care.
没错
I don't.
别告诉别人  好吧?
Don't tell anybody, okay?